

Profile

Currently finishing a Master's Degree in Computer Science. Passionate about data, statistics and machine learning. Almost two years of experience in academic research, and hopefully next year starting a PhD or PDEng in Data Science.

Employment History

Junior Research Fellow at Tecnológico de Monterrey

August 2018 — Present

- Member of the Data Science Research Group.
- Involved in the Scientometric Area.
- Received constructive criticism well and turned it into an opportunity to grow and improve.

Purchasing Quality Engineer at BOSCH

August 2017 — June 2018

- Created monthly scorecards for Bosch's suppliers.
- Responsible for supplier's QAA updates, agreement in which suppliers renew their compromise to deliver zero defect products.
- Delivered and reviewed supplier's samples.

Industrial Engineer Intern at Consulting Firm Lopez Aréchiga e Hijos May 2016 — September 2016

- Successfully carried out a time-motion study analysis for Coca Cola Company's production floor.
- Profitably changed time-motion methodologies for our client BOSCH, from MOST to Methods Time Measurement (MTM).
- Coordinated the Industrial Engineers Intern's Team.

Education

MSc. in Computer Science, Tecnológico de Monterrey, Monterrey, Nuevo León. [91/100]

August 2018 — Present

Awarded with a 100% tuition scholarship by Tecnologico de Monterrey and maintenance scholarship by CONACYT.

BS in Industrial Engineering with a Minor in Strategic Manufacturing Management, CETYS Universidad, Mexicali, Baja California. [94/100]

August 2014 — June 2018

- 1. President of 2016 Engineering Student Council.
- 2. General Manager at the 34th Trascendencias Engineering Symposium.
- 3. Member of *Fortes*, CETYS University Social Leadership Association.
- 4. Study abroad program participant at Deakin University, Melbourne, Australia.

References

Francisco J. Cantú-Ortíz, Ph.D. from Tecnológico de Monterrey fcantu@tec.mx

Details

México, +52 (686) 5 69 63 28 mariodchavezl@gmail.com

Date of birth 08/02/1996

Nationality Mexican

Links

LinkedIn

Skills

Leadership and Teamwork

Effective Communication

Critical Thinking

Statistical Analysis

Data Mining

Python

R

Languages

English

Spanish

Research

Thesis: A Data Analytics Approach to University Teaching Evaluation June 2020

A Data Analytics Approach to Contrast the Performance of Teaching (only) and Research Professors

December 2019

International Journal on Interactive Design and Manufacturing (IJIDeM)

Comparing Performance of Teaching-only and Research Professors

December 2019

Conference Article at the Virtual Concept International Workshop: Event on Innovation in Engineering and Sciences

Comparing Researchers' Teaching Performance with Full Time Professors

June 2019

Speaker at EduData Summit, Research Analytics Stream, Organized by Quacquarelli Symonds (QS) in London, England.

Courses

Epidemiology in Public Health Practice Specialization, John Hopkins University

April 2020 — Present

Deep Learning Specialization, DeepLearning.ai

February 2020 — Present

Becoming a Machine Learning Engineer, Educative.io: Adaptilab

February 2020 — April 2020

Data Science, CodeAcademy

January 2020 — Present